ILGWU Publication "Justice" Index 5780/180
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Publication "Justice" Index
1947-1979
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/180
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents), newsletter.
This collection consists of yearly indexes to Justice, the official organ of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Justice was the official organ of the ILGWU from 1919 to 1995. Editions of Justice were published in English, Italian, Spanish, and Yiddish. When compared side by side, the content of some of these different editions of Justice shows significant differences.
5512159
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Casey Westerman/Nicole Dardia, July 29, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Justice was the official organ of the ILGWU from 1919 to 1995. Editions of Justice were published in English, Italian, Spanish, and Yiddish. When compared side by side, the content of some of these different editions of Justice shows significant differences. The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/051 mf: ILGWU Justice on Microfilm 5780/051 PUBS: ILGWU Publications Justice
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--United States.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5512159
- Subject Index., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Subject Index., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Subject Index., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Subject Index., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Subject Index., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Subject Index., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Subject Index., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Subject Index., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Subject Index., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Subject Indexes., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Scope and Contents
  Two dissimilar subject indexes.
- Subject Index., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Subject Index., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Subject Index., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Subject Index., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Subject Indexes., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Subject Indexes., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Subject Indexes., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Subject Index., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Subject Index., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Subject Index., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Subject Index., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Subject Index., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Subject Index., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Subject Index., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Subject Index., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Subject Index., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Subject Index., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Subject Index., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Subject Index., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Subject Index., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Subject Indexes., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Subject Indexes., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Subject Indexes., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)